# VIKTOR MARTIN

# **Full Stack Developer**

@ viktorsh818@gmail.com

https://www.viktorsh818.github.io

9 13 Tampines St. 11, Singapore Singapore 529453

# **SUMMARY**

I am a full-stack developer with more than 8 years of experience. I have always been customer satisfaction-oriented and continue to apply my knowledge to deliver tangible results in a timely manner. During my career, I fall in love with web development in general—the React and Next.js for front-end development, Django and Node.js for back-end development, and DevOps technologies. Additionally, I enjoy working with Data Structures and Algorithms.

#### **EDUCATION**

09/2010 - 05/2015

Singapore, Singapore

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

**Singapore Institute of Technology** 

GPA 3.9 / 4.0

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### 07/2015 - Present

Freelance Developer

Remote

#### Freelancer

- · Developed and deployed full-stack products and applications for clients.
- · Provided programming instruction to clients, helping them to develop their skills and achieve their goals in software development.
- · Gained experience with various technology stacks, including new technologies such as blockchain.

#### 08/2015 - 05/2023

SIngapore, Singapore

# Full Stack Developer

#### **Guidewire Software**

- · Developed user interface using React for SPA development.
- · Created reusable and scalable React components using state management libraries like Redux and Recoil.
- Utilized Redux Saga and Thunk middleware libraries to handle complex asynchronous workflows and side effects, providing enhanced control and organization to the codebase
- Added real-time communication and data updates to React components using WebSockets, and managed state efficiently with Redux.
- · Utilized Django and Node.js for back-end development, integrated third-party APIs including Twilio.
- · Used Firebase and Strapi to improve the app's functionality, manage data efficiently, boost performance, and provide a great user experience.
- Used GraphQL with Django and React Apollo to make data fetching faster and seamlessly connect the backend and frontend.
- · Implemented CI/CD with the deployment to server.
- · Used Next.js 13 to build React applications that render on the server and generate static page, ensuring optimal performance and enhanced user experiences.
- · Managed a team of two people to develop and deploy a full-stack application in Next.js, Django, GraphQL, and DynamoDB to AWS.
- · Researched users and customers to iterate on the product based on feedback.

# **SKILLS**

#### Languages

JavaScript TypeScript Python PHP C# Go GraphQL Solidity

#### Libraries/APIs

React Node.js Web3.js

#### Frameworks

Next.js React Native Django Django Rest Framework Express.js Laravel ASP.NET

Golang Flutter

Storage

MySQL MongoDB PostgreSQL Amazon DynamoDB

**Paradigms** 

Automation REST Management

# **STRENGTHS**



## **Problem-solving**

Quickly identify and solve complex problems, resulting in 30% improvement in application performance.



# Collaboration

Work effectively in team environments, resulting in on time project delivery and improved customer satisfaction.